# **Takyoung Kim**

# Incoming Ph.D. Student at the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign (UIUC)

 ② youngerous.github.io
 ■ tk30@illinois.edu
 in in/youngerous
 ➤ Google Scholar

### Interests

My research interest lies in the intersection of Natural Language Processing and Communication. I am particularly interested in building communicative language models (LMs) that can understand social and cognitive context, evaluating preference during interaction, and exploring how LMs compose knowledge both from parametric and external sources.

## Education

University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, Urbana, IL, USA

Sep 2024 - Present

Doctor of Philosophy, Computer Science

Korea University, Seoul, South Korea 🗹

Sep 2020 - Aug 2022

Master of Engineering, Industrial Management Engineering

Advisor: Pilsung Kang

Thesis: Relaxing Unrealistic Assumptions of Dataset and Evaluation Metric in Dialogue State Tracking

Sungkyunkwan University, Seoul, South Korea 🗹

Mar 2013 - Aug 2020

Bachelor of Science in Engineering, Interdisciplinary Program of Convergent Software Bachelor of Media & Communication (*Leave of absence for military service: Feb 2015 - Nov 2016*)

### **Publications**

P=Preprint, C=Conference, W=Workshop, J=Journal, \*=Equal Contribution

- [1] DSTEA: Improving Dialogue State Tracking via Entity Adaptive Pre-training \(\begin{align\*}\)
  Yukyung Lee, \(\frac{Takyoung Kim}{}\), Hoonsang Yoon, Pilsung Kang, Junseong Bang, Misuk Kim
  Knowledge-Based Systems (Q1, Impact Factor: 8.8)

  Workshop on Knowledge Augmented Methods for NLP

  KnowledgeNLP, KDD 2023
- [2] KoSBi: A Dataset for Mitigating Social Bias Risks Towards Safer Large Language Model Applications (\*)>

  Hwaran Lee\*, Seokhee Hong\*, Joonsuk Park, <u>Takyoung Kim</u>, Gunhee Kim, Jung-Woo Ha

  Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Industry Track)

  ACL 2023
- [3] SQuARe: A Large-Scale Dataset of Sensitive Questions and Acceptable Responses Created Through Human-Machine Collaboration (\*) Hwaran Lee\*, Seokhee Hong\*, Joonsuk Park, Takyoung Kim, Meeyoung Cha, Yejin Choi, Byoungpil Kim, Gunhee Kim, Eun-Ju Lee, Yong Lim, Alice Oh, Sangchul Park, Jung-Woo Ha

  Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Oral, Best Paper Nomination)

  ACL 2023
- [4] Development of a Framework for Road Test Score Prediction and Significant Keywords Extraction based on Vehicle Specification Data

YongGi Jeong, Kyoosung So, <u>Takyoung Kim</u>, Jina Kim, Seungwan Seo, Seonggye Lee, Sunwoo Kim, Pilsung Kang *Journal of Korean Institute of Industrial Engineers*JKIIE 2023

- [5] Oh My Mistake!: Toward Realistic Dialgoue State Tracking including Turnback Utterances

  Takyoung Kim, Yukyung Lee, Hoonsang Yoon, Pilsung Kang, Junseong Bang, Misuk Kim
  Towards Semi-Supervised and Reinforced Task-Oriented Dialog Systems

  SereTOD, EMNLP 2022
- [6] Mismatch between Multi-turn Dialogue and its Evaluation Metric in Dialogue State Tracking Takyoung Kim, Hoonsang Yoon, Yukyung Lee, Pilsung Kang, Misuk Kim

  Annual Meeting of the Association for Computational Linguistics (Short)

  ACL 2022

#### Preprint & Under Review

[8] Revealing User Familiarity Bias in Task-Oriented Dialogue via Interactive Evaluation Takyoung Kim, Jamin Shin, Young-Ho Kim, Sanghwan Bae, Sungdong Kim

Preprint

# Research Experience

nesearen Experience	
LG AI Research   Advanced Machine Learning Lab, Seoul, South Korea Research Intern (Mentors: Kyungjae Lee, Moontae Lee) Working on enhancing long-form response quality of large language models via planning	Apr 2023 - Present
NAVER AI Lab   Language Research Team, Seongnam, South Korea AR Research Intern (Mentor: Sungdong Kim) Worked on revealing innate bias in task-oriented dialogue research via interactive study [8] Worked on constructing safety benchmark for sensitive questions [3] and social biases [2]	Jul 2022 - Jan 2023
Korea University   Data Science & Business Analytics Lab, Seoul, South Korea  Research Assistant (Advisor: Pilsung Kang) Worked on analyzing realistic biases and limitations of dialogue state tracking [6, 5, 1] Developed algorithms and pipelines in various domains, such as news [7], car [4] and ocean waves	Sep 2020 - Jun 2022
Korea University   Data Science & Business Analytics Lab, Seoul, South Korea Undergraduate Research Intern (Advisor: Pilsung Kang)  Designed spatial/temporal architecture reflecting optical flow for video deepfake detection	Jan 2020 - Aug 2020
Presentations and Talks	
Selective Masking for Task-Adaptive Pre-Training Korean Institute of Industrial Engineers Conference (Spring)	Jun 2021
A Life of Turning into Software Software Edu Fest, Naver Connect Foundation	Jul 2020
Honors and Awards	
Research Ideation Contest   Best Student Feedback Award Korea University	Feb 2021, Dec 2021
MyData Acting Hackathon   The Grand Prize (2nd Place, 2,500\$) Ministry of Science and ICT	Oct 2019
Merit-based Scholarship   Computer Science Coursework Sungkyunkwan University	Spring 2018, Fall 2018
Teaching Experience	
<b>T02459101 - Natural Language Processing</b> Hankuk University of Foreign Studies Teaching Assistant (Instructor: Yukyung Lee)	Feb 2024 - Present
Industrial Machine Learning LG Electronics Head Teaching Assistant (Instructor: Pilsung Kang)	Jan 2022 - Apr 2022
Research Mentoring Hyundai Mobis Research Project Assistant (Instructor: Pilsung Kang)	Jul 2021 - Sep 2021
Industrial Machine Learning and Deep Learning LG Innotek, SK Hynix Teaching Assistant (Instructor: Pilsung Kang)	Jul 2021 - Aug 2021
Academic Service	
Conference Reviewer NeurIPS Datasets & Benchmarks (2022-23), EMNLP (2023), EMNLP EACL (2024)	Industry Track (2023),
Journal Reviewer Knowledge-Based Systems (2023)	
Others ACL Rolling Review (2023-24)	